<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Authors on Jing Lin‘s profile</title><link>http://linjing.io/authors/</link><description>Recent content in Authors on Jing Lin‘s profile</description><generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} linjing.io host on github, imesh.cloud host on netlify. CI/CD by github actions and netlify.Thanks bootcdn support for front libary CDN</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://linjing.io/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jing Lin(林静)</title><link>http://linjing.io/authors/jing-lin%E6%9E%97%E9%9D%99/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://linjing.io/authors/jing-lin%E6%9E%97%E9%9D%99/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gao Yuxian[zhiding.cn]</title><link>http://linjing.io/authors/gao-yuxianzhiding.cn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://linjing.io/authors/gao-yuxianzhiding.cn/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Jing Lin</title><link>http://linjing.io/authors/jing-lin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 15:10:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://linjing.io/authors/jing-lin/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>http://linjing.io/authors/admin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://linjing.io/authors/admin/</guid><description>&lt;p>It has been 10+ years I focus on the industry of application delivery. Initially, I was site engineer to support big banking customers, got lots of practice during there. The experience of 4 years F5 support (TAC) let me know how to control complicated issues, pepole or technical case. I am familar with K8s, Docker, service mesh, NGINX, Ansible, DNS, HTTP, SSL, TCP, UDP, WAF,Loadbalance, Identity Access Management, CDN, Web Accelerator, TCL programming. I like to dig the root of cause when I immerse in troubleshooting. After the TAC role, I moved to F5 APAC consulting team, I am the first one consultant in GCG, during the 4 years, I delivered complicate post-sale and pre-sales projects for APAC customers, this role make me better on time/project management and communications. Then, after that, I decided to take challenge again, so I became the first one Specialist System Engineer in GCG, This is a role that need strong hands-on and pre-sale experience, high level domains knowledge and be innovative. During the role I designed the biggest IPV4/6 smart DNS architecture in China, delivered the first production level F5 PaaS solution. Now I am software solution architect, focus on creating and driving F5 software solutions into cloud native era.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have strong self-learning ability, keep passion to new technology. Also I am blog enthusiast, keep writing blogs since 14 years ago (&lt;a href="https://imesh.club">https://imesh.club&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am familiar with private cloud like openstack/SDN,Vmware. Also good on docker, k8s. I got the Open Group TOGAF v9.2 certificate. I am CNCF Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA #664), own CCNP/MCSE/JNCIS certificates. After F5 accquiring NGINX, I built NGINX Accereditation exam process and questions. It includes 3 levels(Administrator, Professional and Expert). I am the first one F5 certified security solution expert in China. Beside those, I am also interested to open source technology like service mesh(Istio,envoy), observability(ELK, Prometheous, Grafana) etc. I am Cloud Native advocate and is a member of kube-ovn Community Steering Committee.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../img/certifacates-jing.jpg" alt="reviews">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I believe no pain no gain. There is no short path to success. Moving forward and just do it, Never give up.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>